Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Published Works, 1969-2019; Series 4
  - Emerald Coast Review 1989 A Collection of Works of West Florida Writers (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Afterwards Kiss"
  - Lips 1989-Number 15 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Helpmates"; "Death of a Cat"
  - Slow Dancer 22, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "When I had Someone Else's Skin On My Face"; "The Last of the Wine"; "To The Poet Who Knew Her"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 84 No. 4, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Bluebird of Happiness"
  - Journal of NJ Poets Vol. XII No. 2, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Trenton High"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 85 No. 1, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Comments by Grace Cavalieri as a contest judge for the John Williams Andrews Narrative Poetry Prize.
  - Lip Service Vol. 4, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Abbie"; "Throughtforms"
  - Slow Dancer 23, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Sun Lava"; "Others"
  - Slow Dancer 24, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Travel"; "Riding the Wish of a Horse"; "Devy and Me"; "News From the City"
  - Nightsun, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Senior Prom"; "Nightsun interview with Grace Cavalieri 9/27/1990"
  - The Plum Review No. 2, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Florida"; "Canto"
  - Slow Dancer 26, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "What Did They Do With Their Tears"; "Platforms"; "Burning the Box"
  - VIA Voices in Italian Americana a literary and cultural review Vol. 2 No. 1, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Harry's Marriage"
  - Poetry Center 1991 Anthology Passaic County Community College (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Lost Children"
  - US 1 Worksheets Issue No. 24/25, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "For Our Readers"
  - The Jazz Poetry Anthology, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Liberation of Music"
  - The Small Pond Magazine Vol. XXIX No. 2, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Includes a review of Grace Cavalieri's book "Trenton"
  - Window on the Black Sea Bulgarian Poetry in Translation, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Includes poems "Sun" and "City Tree" by Alexander Gerov
  - US 1 Worksheets Issue No. 26/27, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Lavender Night"
  - The Pittsburgh Quarterly Vol. 2 No. 3, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Includes "Cuffed Frays" a work of fiction by Grace Cavalieri
  - Public Hanging II & Containers of the Spirit Art Show, 05/09/1992 --05/29/1992 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Poem by Grace Cavalieri: "You Can't Start The Spiritual Journey Until You Have a Broken Heart"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 87 No. 4, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "End of An Age"
  - Footwork: Paterson Literary Review Issue No. 23, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Perfect Day"
  - la bella figura a choice 1988-1992, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Includes a brief autobiography and the poems "Grandmother" and "To the Poet Who Knew Her"
  - Passenger Vol. 4 No. 2, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Letter"
  - Slow Dancer 29 North American Issue, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Give It Up"
  - VIA Voices in Italian Americana a literary and cultural review Vol. 4 No. 1, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    By Grace Cavalieri "Harvest Kitchen" a work of fiction
  - Antietam Review Vol. XIV, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Tarot Cards XXI. The World"
  - VIA Voices in Italian Americana a literary and cultural review Vol. 5 No. 2, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Three Sestinas for Rafael Cavalieri"
  - Poets & Writers Vol. 22 Issue 2, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Includes article "Grace Cavalieri and "The Poet and the Poem" by Robert Kendall
  - Poets & Writers Vol. 22 Issue 2, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Tantra Press Vol. 1 No. 3, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Tarot Card III. The Empress"; "Tarot Card V. The Hierophant"; "Tarot Card IX. The Hermit"
  - Argonaut Vol. 138 No. 4214, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Pebbles Vol. 1 No. 3, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Tarot Card VI. The Lovers"
  - Indiana Review Vol. 17 No. 1, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Protest"
  - Unsettling America An Anthology of Contemporary Multicultural Poetry, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "The First"; "Grandmother"
  - Ruby One A Journal of Literature and Art, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri: "Blue-Green Spirit"; "Hard Bargain"; "Foot Above Tears"
  - Washington Review Vol. XX No. 4, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Review by Grace Cavalieri of the book "Shake the Parrot Cage"
  - Washington Review Vol. XX No. 6, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Essay by Grace Cavalieri "The Early Years"
  - Hungry As We Are An Anthology of Washington Area Poets, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Tarot Card IV Emperor"
  - Bohemian Bridge Vol. II Issue V, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Tarot Card 1 The Magician"
  - Italian Americana cultural and historical review, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Language Lessons"
  - Wordwright The Quarterly Magazine of Poets and Writers Issue #3, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "The Thing Behind the Words"; "I Will Sing a Song for Your Birthday"; "It May Do Us No Harm To Introduce the Characters"
  - Friendly Creatures the First Friends of Frogs Anthology, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Riding the Wish of a Horse"
  - Black Moon Poetry of Imagination Issue two, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "Uranus"; "Laundry"; "Traffic"
  - Potomac Review 12, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Includes"From Pinecrest Rest Haven" by Grace Cavalieri
  - Belles Lettres A Review of Books by Women Vol. II No. 1, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Includes small write-up about Grace Cavalieri.
  - Journal of NJ Poets 20th Anniversary Issue Vol. XVIII No. 1 and 2, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Things that Hurried By"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 91 No. 3, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Includes Grace Cavalieri reviews "Word Wounds and Water Flowers" by Daniela Gioseffi
  - The First Yes Poems about Communicating, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Harbinger and the Message"
  - True Stories Fiction by Uncommon Women, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Includes work of fiction by Grace Cavalieri "Mr. Sprague Above The Hardware Store"
  - Poet Lore Vol. 92 No. 3, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Includes a review by Grace Cavalieri of "A Life Set for Two" by Robert Kendall
  - Open Door A Poet Lore Anthology 1980-1996, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Les Jardins"
  - Signature Washington Chapter: Women's National Book Association, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Member profile "Grace Cavalieri: An Act of Discovery"
  - Maelstrom one year anniversary issue Vol. 2 Issue 1, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Lilith"
  - Maelstrom Vol. 1 No. 4, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Harry's Marriage"
  - VIA Voices in Italian Americana a literary and cultural review Vol. 9 No. 1, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Letter"
  - Pembroke Magazine No. 30, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Interview "Josephine Jacobsen: An American Classic"
  - Rhapsody in black creative condensation for literary and visual arts Vol. 1 Issue 4, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Magallanic Clouds of Viet Nam"
  - Word Wrights No. 12, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "How It Started"; "Wanting Less"; "Telecommunication"; "The Stalker"
  - Y2K Connecting Nimrod International Journal of Prose and Poetry Vol. 42 No. 2, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "You Can't Start the Spiritual Journey Until You have a Broken Heart"
  - Journal of the IAWM [International Alliance for Women in Music] vol. 10 no. 2, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Includes article "The Composer as Muse: Writing Words for Music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow"
  - Antietam Review Vol. XXIV, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Household Effects"
  - Poetry Center San Jose 25th Anniversary, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Why They Stayed Together"
  - Connecticut Review Vol. XXVI No. 1, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Includes "The Poet and the Poem: An Interview with Lucille Clifton"
  - Echoes Poems for William A selection in honor of William Meredith's 85th Birthday, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Helpmates"
  - D.C. Poets Against The War an Anthology, 06/2003 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Fateema"
  - Gargoyle 48, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Long Night"
  - Rattle poetry for the 21st century Vol. 10 No. 1 Issue No. 21, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Paterson Literary Review 33, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Includes prose by Grace Cavalieri "Chapter 5 Memory in Prose You Could Say She Was Of This Earth"
  - Only The Sea Keeps Poetry of the Tsunami, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "The (Vanished) Seen"; "Day of the Dead"
  - Potomac Review: A Journal of Arts and Humanities, 2005-2006 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "In The Attic of My Grief"
  - The Plum Review, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Includes prose by Grace Cavalieri "From Pinecrest Rest Haven"
  - 10x3 Plus: A Poetry Journal, 2008 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    10x3 Plus
    Contains poems by Cavalieri "Heroin", "Rodin's Assisstant", and "Navy Wife"
  - 10x3 plus a poetry journal #4, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    Poems by Grace Cavalieri in this issue include "Equipoise" for poet Robert Sargent at 94
  - 10x3 Plus: A poetry Journal #7, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - ABZ: A Poetry Magazine no. 2, 2007 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Hot Pants"
  - Acqua Sul Sole, 09/2007 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Aerial #2, 1986 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Emotional Environments"
  - The Agni Review (to Ezra Pound), 1973 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri that is untitled
  - The Agni Review, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "I Am Not Lazy. This is One Thing I Am Not"
  - Ambrosia: Journal of Haiku, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    Ambrosia
    Contains a haiku by Cavalieri
  - The American Poetry Review vol. 21 no. 6, 11/1992 --12/1992 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    Includes interview of Joseph Brodsky by Grace Cavalieri.
  - The American Poetry Review vol. 24 no. 2, 03/1995 --04/1995 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    Includes interview with Rita Dove by Grace Cavalieri.
  - The American Poetry Review vol. 26 no. 2, 03/1997 --04/1997 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    Includes interview with Robert Hass by Grace Cavalieri.
  - The American Poetry Review Vol. 38 No. 4, 07/2009-08/2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    Grace Cavalieri interivewed Kay Ryan
  - American Poetry Review: Interview with Mark Strand, 08/1994 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Anthology of Appalachian Writers Volume IV, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - The Anthology of Mentor Poetry for the Sixties, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Love Poem"
  - Antietam Review vol. 7, 1978 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Returning"
  - Antietam Review vol. 8, 1988 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    Includes interview with Grace Cavalieri.
  - Antietam Review vol. 20, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Old Woman in the Bed"
  - Antietam Review vol. 24, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Apostrophe, 1973 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Abortion"
  - Ariel no. 1, 1984 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Working for the Government"
  - Arts and Activities vol. 86 no. 3, 11/1979 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    The cover includes a silk screen print by Mary Ellen Long with Grace Cavalieri poem
  - ASHA vol. 32 [American Speech-Language-Hearing Assocation], 09/1990 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Harbinger and the Message"
  - Ask the Advisor: Poetry Today Magazine, 08/2008 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - The Atlantic Review vol. 1 no. 2, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Orphanage"
  - At the Gate: Departures and Arrivals, 2011; Series 4 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Tomato Pies, 25 Cents"
  - Baltimore Renaissance: Poetry vol. 8, 1980 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "The Child"
  - Bartleby, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "Self-Portrait" and "Moderation"
  - Belles Lettres vol. 11 no. 1, 01/1996 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    includes a brief biography and review of Grace Cavalieri's book Migrations.
  - Beltway Magazine, September 20, 2007 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Beyond Literacy: Reviewed by Cavalieri (Box 86, Folder 7)
    Beyond Literacy
    Art Project reviewed by Grace Cavalieri
  - Blind Alleys a journal of contemporary literature Vol. 2 No. 2, 1985; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    This issue includes poems by Devy Bendit. A good friend of Grace Cavalieri.
  - Bridges Review Vol. 6, 2017; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Caesura: The Journal of Poetry Center San Jose, 2002 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "For the Faithful"; "Your Success Just Has to Catch Up With You"; "Athlete of God"
  - The Call: an anthology of women's writing, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    Poems by Grace Cavalieri include "The Morning is Fair to Everyone," "Owning the Not So Distant World," "Missing in Action," "Postscript;" "River of Reward," and "Rodin's Assistant"
  - Calvert, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "There is a Piece of Virgin Forest Around My Neck. The Living Come With Equal Felicity"
  - Catalyst, 1986 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri "Requiem Mass"
  - Chelsea 81, 2006 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    This issue includes a dedication to Grace Cavalieri.
  - Chesapeake Life, 2009 April; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    This issue includes information about "Anna Nicole" by Grace Cavalieri
  - Chrysalides by Kathie Isaac-Luke, Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Coal: A Poetry Anthology, 2006 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Age of Optimism"
  - The College Observer, Williamsburg, VA, 12/15/1970 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "For Just You, Who Knows My Name"
  - Colloquy vol. 2 no. 4, 04/1969 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri one-act play "The Late and Blooming Early Branch"
  - Come Celebrate with Me: a VOICES memorial tribute to Lucille Clifton, 2011; Series 4 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Don't Undersell Yourself"
  - Connections Literary Magazine vol. 8 no. 1, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri interview "Connections with Grace Cavalieri"
  - Contemporary American Theater Festival Review, undated (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Creation, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "September"
  - CT Review (Connecticut Review) Vol. 28 no. 1, 2006 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Heart For It"
  - CT Review (Connecticut Review) Vol.30 no.2, 2007 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    CT Review
    Includes review of Louise Gluck's "Averno".
  - CT Review (Connecticut Review) Vol. 31 No. 2, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the pome "The Morning is Fair to Everyone" by Grace Cavalieri
  - DC's Urbancode, 02/2008 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    DC Urbancode
    Cavalieri interview with Alberto Gaitan
  - December vol. 15 no. 1 and 2, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Three from 'Points in Space'" and "Virtues"
  - December, vol. 26, no. 2, 2015; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    Includes Cavalieri poem "Athena"
  - Dickinsonian, 2000 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Blue-Green Spirit" and "Tarot Card IX: Temperance"
  - Dramatics vol. 43 no. 5, 02/1972 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri one-act play "Hush, No One is Listening"
  - Dramatics vol. 44 no. 1, 10/1972 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri interview "Playwriting: The Organic Art"
  - Dramatis Personae Quarterly, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri one-act drama "The Late and Blooming Early Branch"
  - Dryad No. 14 and 15, 1977; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Encore vol. 7 no. 4, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Waiting for the Water to Boil"
  - Evolving City: Poetry Quarterly, 10/2007 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Excerpt from "The City", undated (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - The Falcon no. 1, 08/1970 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Comfortable with Creation... Said Saint Paul... on the Fourth Sunday"
  - The Falcon no. 4, 03/1972 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri review of A Man Running in the Rain
  - The Falcon no. 16, 1978; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    Yannis Ritsos selected poems 1938-1975
  - Festival of Religion and the Arts 1969 Poetry Award (Box 76, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Prayer" and "Entreaty"
  - Figurative Realism #100, Circa 2018; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 2 no. 1, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Dogwood"
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 2 no. 2, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Morning Bridge"
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 2 no. 3, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Flouting the Ground"
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 3 no. 2, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Here", "The Devoted Dead", and "Hymns for the House"
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 3 no. 3, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Cookies and Wine"
  - Fine Arts Discovery vol. 4 no. 2, 1970 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "On the Bank" and "In the Cabin"
  - Fledgling Rag, Issue 16, Circa 2015; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    Includes Cavalieri poems "Taking One's Self Back", Everything Is Smaller Than the Truth", "Alzheimer's Again", "Harbinger", "1950", "Death Is Cool Desire Is Hot", "Being Japanese".
  - Flights: Literary Journal of Sinclair Community College, undated (Box 86, Folder 13)
    Flights
    Contains poems by Cavalieri: "Mama Don't Allow no Blues or Jazz", "After the Flood", "Art Muesum" and "By What Route"
  - Freelance vol. 7 no. 3, undated (Box 76, Folder 13)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Peeling Off"
  - Freelance vol. 8 no. 1, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Major Pettigrew"
  - Friendly Creatures, no. 2, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Trenton High" and "The Twilight on the Chair"
  - Ginosko Short Story & Poetry, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - The Goliards no. 7, 06/1969 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Yielding to the Pedestrians" and "The Highway"
  - Graffiti no. 4, 1975 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri short story "Prayers and Prophesies"
  - Greg Mosson Review, undated (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Hard Pressed no. 1, 1975 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Citizenship"
  - Harpur Palate vol. 4 issue 2, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Ellsworth Avenue"
  - The Horses Before they Start, 06/2008 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - House Organ, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - The Hot Skin, 1983 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    This issue includes handwritten note to Grace from author Melissa Clark
  - Hot Sonnets, 2011; Series 4 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "Anna Nicole's Dream"
  - Hymns for the House, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Icarus vol. 1 no. 3, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "The Color of My Hair" and "Watching the Children"
  - If #1, 2007 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    If #1
    Contains poem by Cavalieri, "If So, I'll be Grateful to You"
  - The Imaginary Invalid, undated (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - The Inner Well, 01/1968 --02/1968 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Hole Out" and "The Louder the Day"
  - Interview with Mark Doty: oranges and sardines, 05/2008 (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - Interview with Eavan Boland, undated (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - Interviews: Oranges and Sardines, undated (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Innuendos by Cavalieri, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 22)
  - Italian Americana: Cultural and Historical Review vol. 14 no. 1, 1996 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    This issue includes a review of the Grace Cavalieri book Poems New and Selected. The review was written by Pasquale Verdicchio.
  - Italian Americana: Cultural and Historical Review vol. 17 no. 1, 1999 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Athletes of God"
  - Jean's Journal vol. 6 no. 2, 1968 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Upon Discovering the Corpse"
  - Journal of Kentucky Studies vol. 16, 09/1999 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "What Moves"
  - Kauri no. 26, 05/1968 --06/1968 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    Includes an untitled poem by Grace Cavalieri
  - Kauri no. 27, 07/1968 --08/1968 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri one-act play "Hush No One Is Listening"
  - Kauri no. 28, 09/1968 --10/1968 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri play "The Keeper of the Station"
  - Kauri no. 30, 01/1969 --02/1969 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri play "The Poem Which Wrote Me"
  - Kauri thru Will Inman no. 108, 1969 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    This issue includes a dedication to Grace on the title page.
  - Kauri no. 31, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Revolution"
  - Kauri no. 33, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Come to a Wedding", "Down the Road", "Life and Death in Christ's Own Time", and Departing Gethsemane"
  - Kestrel: Issue 21, 2005 (Box 86, Folder 23)
    Kestrel
    Includes Cavalieri's poems: "The Day I had an Affair" and "Get it Right"
  - Let Us Now Praise Famous Women: Beltway Magazine, undated (Box 86, Folder 24)
  - Lips, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Lips, no. 44/45, 2016; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    Includes Cavalieri poem "1972".
  - Lips No. 48/49, 2018; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Little Patuxet Review, 2008 (Box 86, Folder 25)
  - Little Patuxent Review, Issue 19, 2016; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    Includes Cavalieri poem "Bacchae"